# **Jacob William**

# **Software Engineering Intern**

I'm a Full Stack Software Engineer specialized in React, NodeJS, Python, C#, and many other languages and frameworks. I also specialize in developing secure and optimized applications using the proper algorithms and software engineering practices. I believe that languages and frameworks are just tools and what matters is who's using them.

# **Experience**

#### 2018-11 present

## **Software Engineering Intern**

Aclara Technologies, LLC

- Developing manufacturing software in C# with real-time analytics, employees management, and fetching data from multiple databases and 3rd party APIs
- MVC design that includes database models, controllers, and views
- Implemented using complex data structures such as binary search trees to handle the large data fetched from data base and API

#### 2018-05 -2018-07

## **Software Engineering Intern**

Open Learning Exchange, Inc

- Worked on Android and Angular projects
- Implemented UI for varies of views and backend logic
- Anticipated in code reviews, pull requests, and bugs on GitHub

## **Education**

#### 2017-03 -2020-04

#### Southern New Hampshire University, BA in Computer Science

- Taken CS core courses such as: Data Structures and Algorithms course, Advance Database courses, Operation Systems course, OOP course, and varies Intro to programming courses in different languages.
- GPA 3.6

# **Projects**

#### **Cell Productivity**

(Internship Project)

- Developed using C# and Microsoft SQL 2017
- Features real-time analytics, order management and tracking features
- Incorporated in-app messaging system using MongoDB and web sockets
- Handles massive data that are featured from a Workday API

#### Cool It!

https://github.com/onlyserenity/cool-it

- Developed cross-platform, real-time application using React, Redux, Electron, and Firebase that allows users to chat and create their own groups.
- Incorporated a storage system with caching capabilities to store loaded media and make the application perform faster.

#### **Authenticator-ExpressJs**

https://github.com/onlyserenity/authenticator-expressis

- Developed using Nodejs and Expressjs that always a quick plug-and-config to users who wish to implement authentication system and secure RESTful API to their front end applications
- Implemented bcrypt to encrypt sensitive user's data before saving on the database
- Used MongoDB with schemas to design the users model

# **Real World Algorithms**

https://github.com/onlyserenity/CS260\_DATA\_STRUCTURES

- Used C++ to implement concepts learned during my 2nd year in college and implemented a real-world project that reads data from large excel sheets
- It features CRUD operations as well as search functionality.
- Different part of the application demonstrates the performance difference in using Binary Trees, Sorting algorithms and Vectors, Linked-lists and other data structures

## **Personal Info**

#### **Address**

New Hampshire

#### **Phone**

603-892-7597

#### E-mail

amjedcha@gmail.com

#### **GitHub**

https://github.com/onlyserenity

### **Portfolio**

https://jacobwi.io

#### LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/amjedch

# **Software**

React

Very Advance

NodeJS (ES5, ES6)

Very Advance

LESS, CSS, SCSS (including @emotions and @styled-components)

Very Advance

C#

Very Advance

Python

Advance

Redux

Swift

Semi-Advance

Android in Java

Semi-Advanced

Intermediate

GatsbyJS with GraphQL

Intermediate